<resources>
    <string name="app_name">nPuzzle</string>

    <string name="about">
        Author: Roberto Bracaglia Morante
        \nSoftware used: Android-Studio, GIMP and Inkscape.
        \nNo commercial purposes, no ads, no special permissions required.
        \n\nA couple of things to know about this app:
        \n\nThe random generator does not cheat, it only checks if the permutation can be solved or not,
        which means there is the chance of generating a permutation already resolved.
        One on 181440 in case 8, and one on more than 10 trillions for case 15.
        If that happens to you, go play the lottery now, it could be your lucky day ;)
        \n\nThe resolution algorithm is an ida* that relies on admissible heuristic
        (Manahattan distances and linear conflicts), its result is always an optimal solution.
        It is written in native C++ code for performance reasons.
        While case 8 resolves on average in less than one thousandth of a second,
        case 15 takes on average a few seconds, a few minutes in the worst cases
        with more than a billion of nodes expanded.
        \n\nFor case 15 it is possible to stop the algorithm between heuristic bounds.
        What does it mean? Let\'s say: we started the searching to resolve a permutation
        that has initial heuristic 40, and the same parmutation takes 56 moves to be resolved.
        After half a second we click the stop button while the search within the bound 50 in not yet complete,
        the algorithm will continue until the end of the current limit.
        In the meanwhile an hourglass appears on the \"magic button\",
        and it disappears when the algorithm reaches the \"Java flag\" placed before the next heuristic bound.
        That\'s because it is not possible to put that flag inside the C++ code unless the latter is further splitted,
        but this would result in a performance hit that would make its implementation no more worthwhile.
        \n\nFor performance reasons can be run only a search at a time, because
        while the non-interactive search is still open, it would be temporarily concurrent with the new one,
        reducing the resources available for the latter, and this is not acceptable.
        \n\nThat\'s it!
    </string>

</resources>
